<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>workshop on Fink broker</title>
    <link>https://fink-broker.org/tags/workshop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in workshop on Fink broker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fink-broker.org/tags/workshop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fink Brazil</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2024-05-27-fink-brazil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2024-05-27-fink-brazil/</guid>
      <description>The Fink Brazil workshop took place at CBPF, Rio de Janeiro, from 6 to 10 June 2024. This event brought together researchers interested in exploring the potential applications of Fink data, both in the context of the Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF), as well as the upcoming Vera Rubin Observatory Large Survey of Space and Time (LSST).
The program included keynote speakers and contributed talks, posters and tutorials that will help prepare the local community for the arrival of LSST data, maximizing the scientific output of the alert stream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ozFink</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2023-05-05_ozfink/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2023-05-05_ozfink/</guid>
      <description>Our first Australian workshop was held in Melbourne between the 3 and 5th of May 2023. We had over 50 simultaneous participants both in person and online. It was a great moment to share current facilities, research and start setting the bases for Rubin LSST first light!
We had a very dynamic schedule with talks about Rubin, Australia LSST involvement, facilities at all wavelengths both in Australia and New Zealand, high-energy, radio, optical, gravitational wave transients, variables, potential theoretical observations, services in Australia, discussion sessions, and much more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ozFink - Save the date!</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2023-04-28_ozfink/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2023-04-28_ozfink/</guid>
      <description>Fink next workshop will be held on May 3 to 5 at Swinburne University of Technology, Melbourne, Australia. This workshop will develop collaboration across Australian research groups, observing facilities and the Fink collaboration. This meeting will be in hybrid format with participants both in person and on zoom. More information at https://www.ozgrav.org/ozfink-workshop-2023.html.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LSST enabling science 2020 broker workshop</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2020-09-17-lsst-enabling-science-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2020-09-17-lsst-enabling-science-part1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to enable new science with the LSST alert stream, brokers are developing a new layer in the time domain ecosystem, experimenting with new ways of enriching and filtering these data. A diversity of solutions are being tested, but there is a need for more interaction between brokers, their community of users, and the alert generation teams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Fink Workshop @ IJCLab</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2020-01-28-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2020-01-28-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The First Fink Workshop will take place at IJCLab on the 6 February 2020, just after the LSST-France meeting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
