<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Fink broker</title>
    <link>https://fink-broker.org/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Fink broker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fink-broker.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructures in Fink</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2021-12-17-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2021-12-17-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>Fink infrastructure Let&amp;rsquo;s take the opportunity of the bad turn of recent events to talk and learn a bit more on the infrastructure in place for Fink.
Fink is deployed on the cloud, that is each box in the Figure is an independent set of machines where specific software are running and executing tasks.
Nightly alert processing The central part of the processing in Fink is the Apache Spark cluster (see fink-broker).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fink maintenance</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2021-12-16-maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2021-12-16-maintenance/</guid>
      <description>Power outage strikes back This year, we had regular power outages at the VirtualData center, mainly due to a weak and old electrical network at the University. The IT teams at IJCLab regularly restarted all machines and services in a short amount of time after hard cuts (included evenings and week-ends!), and we designed more and more robust and automatic systems to keep the whole infrastructure healthy and operative after going completely crazy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fink data statistics</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2021-12-01-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2021-12-01-statistics/</guid>
      <description>Check out the new page about Fink processed data statistics on the Science Portal: heatmap, daily statistics, timelines, and more! These statistics are updated once a day, after the ZTF observing night.
The header tells you about the last night we had data, the number of processed alerts for this night, the total number of processed alerts since 2019/11/01, as well as how many got a label by Fink.
Heatmap The Heatmap tab shows the number of alerts processed by Fink for each night since the beginning of our operations (2019/11/01).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fink Science Portal 0.10</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2021-09-27-science-portal-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2021-09-27-science-portal-updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out the version 0.10 of the Science Portal! Several new features: DNS for the portal, crossmatch with LIGO/Virgo maps, query string, and as always&amp;hellip; a lot of bug fixes!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fink Science Portal 0.9</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2021-08-10-science-portal-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2021-08-10-science-portal-updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out the version 0.9 of the Science Portal: Several new features: constellation names, preview of alert information, shiny new buttons, link to SNAD, and&amp;hellip; a lot of bug fixes!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fink Science Portal 0.8</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2021-07-05-science-portal-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2021-07-05-science-portal-updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out the version 0.8 of the Science Portal: increased features, boosted conesearch, improved layout, support for mobile platforms, and many more!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fink Science Portal</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2020-11-11-science-portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2020-11-11-science-portal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Fink development team is happy to announce the deployment of the Fink Science Portal!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fink white paper</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2020-09-23-white-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2020-09-23-white-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a year of activities, the Fink team is proud to release its &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2009.10185&#34;&gt;first paper&lt;/a&gt;! The team made of researchers and engineers worked restlessly to make Fink comes true. Congratulations to all!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LSST enabling science 2020 broker workshop</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2020-09-17-lsst-enabling-science-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2020-09-17-lsst-enabling-science-part1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to enable new science with the LSST alert stream, brokers are developing a new layer in the time domain ecosystem, experimenting with new ways of enriching and filtering these data. A diversity of solutions are being tested, but there is a need for more interaction between brokers, their community of users, and the alert generation teams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fink is listening to ZTF!</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2020-02-01-mouztf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2020-02-01-mouztf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that Fink has signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with the Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF) Project on 2020, January 29.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Fink Workshop @ IJCLab</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2020-01-28-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2020-01-28-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The First Fink Workshop will take place at IJCLab on the 6 February 2020, just after the LSST-France meeting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter of Intent for LSST community broker</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2020-01-10-loi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2020-01-10-loi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2019, Fink decided to participate to the LSST call for community broker. The first step was the submission of a Letter of Intent to LSST in Summer 2019 to describe the project, and our goals: &lt;em&gt;Fink - a new generation of astronomy broker based on Active Learning and Apache Spark.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2019-12-17-welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2019-12-17-welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fink is a broker infrastructure enabling a wide range of applications and services to connect to large streams of alerts issued from telescopes all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
