<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Members on Fink broker</title>
    <link>https://fink-broker.org/tags/members/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Members on Fink broker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://fink-broker.org/tags/members/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Joining Fink</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/joining/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/joining/</guid>
      <description>If you want to know more about Fink and our recent releases and science results, you can follow us on twitter @FinkBroker and check our news.
You can join the Fink collaboration by filling this form. You will be then subscribed to our mailing list and receive relevant news and information about our general meetings.
If you have already a science project in mind (not necessary to join Fink), you can also submit a Fink community project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/members/</guid>
      <description>Management Team  Emille E. O. Ishida (PI) - CNRS/LPC Clermont, IT department Anais Möller (PI) - Swinburne University, Centre for Astrophysics and Supercomputing Julien Peloton (PI) - CNRS/IJCLab, IT department  You can contact us at contact(at)fink-broker.org for more information.
Development Team  Julien Peloton (Lead) - CNRS/IJCLab, IT department Julius Hrivnac (database) - CNRS/IJCLab, IT department Marco Leoni (machine learning) - Université Paris-Saclay, IT department Adrien Ramparison (cloud management, deployment, monitoring) - CNRS/IJCLab, IT department  Fink members &amp;amp; collaborators Argentina  International Center for Advanced Studies, Physical Sciences Institute, San Martin University: M.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
