<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>award on Fink broker</title>
    <link>https://fink-broker.org/tags/award/</link>
    <description>Recent content in award on Fink broker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fink-broker.org/tags/award/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Science Portal 3.0</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2023-12-08-science-portal-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2023-12-08-science-portal-3/</guid>
      <description>The Fink Science Portal 3.0 is out! This new version contains a lot of improvements and new features, with a huge contribution from Sergey Karpov (FZU). The full list of code change can be found in the release notes, and we detail below the main changes.
New features This new release brings a lot of new features. Regarding the general layout, we added a responsive menubar on top to complement the current togglable sidebar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open science prize for Free Software in research 2023</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2023-11-29-open-science-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2023-11-29-open-science-award/</guid>
      <description>We are proud to announce that the Fink team has been awarded the open science prize for Free Software in research 2023 by the French Ministry of Research!
The award recognizes projects and research teams working to develop and disseminate free software, contributing to the construction of a crucial common good. These awards recognize the production of free software as a contribution and a result of research. They highlight exceptional or highly promising achievements, which can inspire both the scientific community and society as a whole.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
