<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fink broker</title>
    <link>https://fink-broker.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Fink broker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fink-broker.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fink is expanding!</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2023-01-25-fink-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2023-01-25-fink-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Fink broker release 2.9 includes new science modules exploring anomaly detection, time-series transformer for transient classification, and additional associations to various catalogs of astronomical objects. Additionally, the Fink Science Portal 2.1 release adds a lot of new features!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data transfer at scale</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2023-01-17-data-transfer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2023-01-17-data-transfer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce a new service in Fink to explore and transfer historical data at scale: &lt;a href=&#34;https://fink-portal.org/download&#34;&gt;https://fink-portal.org/download&lt;/a&gt;. This service lets users to select any observing nights between 2019 and now, apply filters, define the content of the output, and stream data directly to anywhere!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fink Science Portal 2.0</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2022-08-30-science-portal-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2022-08-30-science-portal-updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out the details of the version 2.0 of the Science Portal. A shiny new interface, better performance, and some new features or bug fixes (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/astrolabsoftware/fink-science-portal/releases/tag/2.0&#34;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt;). Do not hesitate to give your feedback, and propose missing features!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fink Science Portal 1.3</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2022-07-05-science-portal-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2022-07-05-science-portal-updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out the details of the version 1.3 of the Science Portal. This is the last release for the version 1, and the next release will be a major one!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fink Collaboration Meeting</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2022-06-10-fink-collaboration-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2022-06-10-fink-collaboration-meeting/</guid>
      <description>We had our first in-person Collaboration Meeting last month in Annecy. This was 3 years after the start of the project, which included 2 years of pandemic. It was a pleasure to host and work with so many scientists!
The two days were super active, with a lot of discussions and hands-on tutorials. We were super happy to see all the new developments, and such a diversity in the science topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fink Science Portal 1.2</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2022-06-08-science-portal-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2022-06-08-science-portal-updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out the version 1.2 of the Science Portal!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar System Science with Fink</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2022-01-28-sso-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2022-01-28-sso-science/</guid>
      <description>Linking alerts to known moving objects Each night, Fink receives alerts from the public survey of the Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF). The alert stream primarily includes events from flux transients and variables, but it also contains a large fraction of Solar System objects (SSO). Alert candidates are typically linked to an object on the sky by a cone search at the position of the alert. While this allows us to easily retrieve the brightness variation of a static object on the sky over time, this does not work if one wants to study a moving object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interface changes</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2022-01-18-what-changed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2022-01-18-what-changed/</guid>
      <description>API changes With the recent maintenance, we did a number of changes to sanitize the infrastructure and the pipelines. Some of these changes breaks the compatibility with older Fink versions. All changes apply from fink-broker version 1.4+ and fink-science version 0.5+, with a new schema.
Active Learning module We introduced a name change for the output of the module. The old rfscore field is now replaced by rf_snia_vs_nonia. The module itself did not change, and the values remain the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power failures at the University</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2022-01-18-power-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2022-01-18-power-failure/</guid>
      <description>Work has been done! This year, we had regular power outages at the VirtualData center, mainly due to a weak and old electrical network at the University. The IT teams at IJCLab regularly restarted all machines and services in a short amount of time after hard cuts (included evenings and week-ends!), and we designed more and more robust and automatic systems to keep the whole infrastructure healthy and operative after going completely crazy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh my God, they killed Kenny!</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2022-01-17-maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2022-01-17-maintenance/</guid>
      <description>Storage system failure The last reboot of machines (14/12) had revealed a serious problem in our storage system. Long story short, a large part of Fink data could not be recovered, making difficult to get some services back online, and we had no backup for this. It is yet unclear what happened exactly, but most likely a manipulation of the journal of transations in November that silently corrupted the system, only revealed a month later when the systems were rebooted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructures in Fink</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2021-12-17-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2021-12-17-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>Fink infrastructure Let&amp;rsquo;s take the opportunity of the bad turn of recent events to talk and learn a bit more on the infrastructure in place for Fink.
Fink is deployed on the cloud, that is each box in the Figure is an independent set of machines where specific software are running and executing tasks.
Nightly alert processing The central part of the processing in Fink is the Apache Spark cluster (see fink-broker).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fink data statistics</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2021-12-01-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2021-12-01-statistics/</guid>
      <description>Check out the new page about Fink processed data statistics on the Science Portal: heatmap, daily statistics, timelines, and more! These statistics are updated once a day, after the ZTF observing night.
The header tells you about the last night we had data, the number of processed alerts for this night, the total number of processed alerts since 2019/11/01, as well as how many got a label by Fink.
Heatmap The Heatmap tab shows the number of alerts processed by Fink for each night since the beginning of our operations (2019/11/01).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fink Science Portal 0.10</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2021-09-27-science-portal-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2021-09-27-science-portal-updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out the version 0.10 of the Science Portal! Several new features: DNS for the portal, crossmatch with LIGO/Virgo maps, query string, and as always&amp;hellip; a lot of bug fixes!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fink Science Portal 0.9</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2021-08-10-science-portal-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2021-08-10-science-portal-updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out the version 0.9 of the Science Portal: Several new features: constellation names, preview of alert information, shiny new buttons, link to SNAD, and&amp;hellip; a lot of bug fixes!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fink Science Portal 0.8</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2021-07-05-science-portal-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2021-07-05-science-portal-updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out the version 0.8 of the Science Portal: increased features, boosted conesearch, improved layout, support for mobile platforms, and many more!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fink Science Portal</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2020-11-11-science-portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2020-11-11-science-portal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Fink development team is happy to announce the deployment of the Fink Science Portal!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fink white paper</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2020-09-23-white-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2020-09-23-white-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a year of activities, the Fink team is proud to release its &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2009.10185&#34;&gt;first paper&lt;/a&gt;! The team made of researchers and engineers worked restlessly to make Fink comes true. Congratulations to all!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LSST enabling science 2020 broker workshop</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2020-09-17-lsst-enabling-science-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2020-09-17-lsst-enabling-science-part1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to enable new science with the LSST alert stream, brokers are developing a new layer in the time domain ecosystem, experimenting with new ways of enriching and filtering these data. A diversity of solutions are being tested, but there is a need for more interaction between brokers, their community of users, and the alert generation teams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fink is listening to ZTF!</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2020-02-01-mouztf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2020-02-01-mouztf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that Fink has signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with the Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF) Project on 2020, January 29.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Fink Workshop @ IJCLab</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2020-01-28-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2020-01-28-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The First Fink Workshop will take place at IJCLab on the 6 February 2020, just after the LSST-France meeting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter of Intent for LSST community broker</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2020-01-10-loi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2020-01-10-loi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2019, Fink decided to participate to the LSST call for community broker. The first step was the submission of a Letter of Intent to LSST in Summer 2019 to describe the project, and our goals: &lt;em&gt;Fink - a new generation of astronomy broker based on Active Learning and Apache Spark.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/2019-12-17-welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/2019-12-17-welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fink is a broker infrastructure enabling a wide range of applications and services to connect to large streams of alerts issued from telescopes all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/about/</guid>
      <description>Fink is a community driven project, open to anyone, that processes time-domains alert streams and connects them with follow-up facilities and science teams. Fink broker has been selected as a community broker to process the full stream of transient alerts from the Vera C. Rubin Observatory. Since 2020, we are processing the alert stream from the Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF).
Fink&amp;rsquo;s processed data stream from ZTF can be accessed through our science portal and our API (with tutorials).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joining Fink</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/joining/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/joining/</guid>
      <description>If you want to know more about Fink and our recent releases and science results, you can follow us on twitter @FinkBroker and check our news.
You can join the Fink collaboration by filling this form. You will be then subscribed to our mailing list and receive relevant news and information about our general meetings.
If you have already a science project in mind (not necessary to join Fink), you can also submit a Fink community project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/papers/</guid>
      <description>List of publications from the Fink collaboration and the larger astronomy community that uses Fink public data.
2023  The Tiny Time-series Transformer: Low-latency High-throughput Classification of Astronomical Transients using Deep Model Compression, Tarek Allam Jr., Julien Peloton, Jason D. McEwen
2022   Finding active galactic nuclei through Fink, Etienne Russeil, Emille E. O. Ishida, Roman Le Montagner, Julien Peloton, Anais Moller
 Enabling the discovery of fast transients: A kilonova science module for the Fink broker, B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team</title>
      <link>https://fink-broker.org/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fink-broker.org/members/</guid>
      <description>Management Team  Emille E. O. Ishida (PI) - CNRS/LPC Clermont, IT department Anais Möller (PI) - Swinburne University, Centre for Astrophysics and Supercomputing Julien Peloton (PI) - CNRS/IJCLab, IT department  You can contact us at contact(at)fink-broker.org for more information.
Development Team  Julien Peloton (Lead) - CNRS/IJCLab, IT department Julius Hrivnac (database) - CNRS/IJCLab, IT department Marco Leoni (machine learning) - Université Paris-Saclay, IT department Adrien Ramparison (cloud management, deployment, monitoring) - CNRS/IJCLab, IT department  Fink members &amp;amp; collaborators Argentina  International Center for Advanced Studies, Physical Sciences Institute, San Martin University: M.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
